# MICHAEL STILES

### https://github.com/mstiles01 | (903) 343-5766 | mstiles01@icloud.com

# **Professional Summary**

Skilled software developer and management professional with over 6 years of experience in leadership, developing creative customer solutions, and driving iterative process improvements. Extensive experience in application and software development, programming and scripting languages, and database management. Continually exceeds expectations by building valuable partnerships and works well with people at all levels of the organization including stakeholders, customers, and team members.

### Skills

- Cross-Functional Leadership & People Management
- Technical Project Management & Development
- Operations Management & Strategic Planning
- Superior Customer Service & Client Engagement
- Software Development & Application Development
- Data Structures & Database Management

- Root-Cause Troubleshooting & Technical
- Support
- Strong Scripting & Programming Knowledge
- Team Building & Talent Development
- Process Improvements & Iterative Design
- Creative Problem Solving & Complex Analysis
- Excellent Verbal & Written Communication

## Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, C#, ADO.NET, MVC, Entity/Identity Framework, AWS, Python, Django, AWS: EC2, IAM, Elastic BeanStalk, Serverless Lambda, DynamoDB, Gateway & Cognito, ECS, ECR, Docker

# Work History

Software Developer, Student

07/19 to 09/2020

#### **Nashville Software School**

- Developing proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, C#, ADO.NET, MVC, Entity/Identity Framework, AWS.
- Skillfully working in a tech stack comprised of JavaScript and React on the client side and C#/.NET on the server side.
- Successfully producing clean, efficient code based on specifications while testing and deploying programs and systems.
- Proactively fixing and improving existing software, integrating software components and third-party programs.
- Troubleshooting, debugging and upgrading existing software, gathering user feedback and executing key improvements.
- Conducting single-page application development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and several styling libraries.
- Creating, updating, and managing databases with multiple methodologies including SQL and Entity frameworks.
- Developing full-stack applications with Identity framework, gained experience with essential frameworks and tools.
- Acquired the requisite skills to solve complex software problems and to quickly and efficiently learn new software.
- Spearheaded a number of complex technical projects from inception to completion to apply to fictional scenarios.
- Designed and developed an application to manage internal resources, providing users with superior functionality.
- Designing and developing BreakBread, a community recipe app inspired by the user-specific data mined from comments.

#### **Customer Success Manager**

05/2018 to 06/2019

#### ServiceSource

- Successfully captured customers' product expectations, experiences, satisfaction, and abandonment propensity.
- Leveraged qualitative feedback and quantitative measurement to design, develop, and implement key initiatives.
- Managed the analysis of SMB and volume segments, conducted regular health checks at recurring intervals.
- Continually gauged product satisfaction and value attainment, provided superior customer service and engagement.
- Effectively assessed client needs and requirements to adequately recommend satisfactory product solutions.
- Proactively maintained the CRM software to ensure all relevant data was captured in a timely and efficient manner.

- Established customer support practices, creating policies and procedures to optimize the customer experience.
- Conducted extensive research on competitor's customer success programs, analyzed data to identify the best practices.
- Demonstrated a deep knowledge of company products, provided technical support and product training to customers.
- Educated customers on the flexibility and capabilities of company software to increase customer loyalty and retention.
- Supervising staff and providing on the job training or mentoring to new employees, established clear retention goals.

**Assistant Manager** 08/2014 to 04/2018

#### Air Rover

- Confidently helped manage the day-to-day operations, strategic planning, and strategy implementation for the company.
- Ensured regulatory compliance for units in all phases of development of assembly to meet government rated orders.
- Maintained inventory levels to ensure parts were available and on hand when specific components were required.
- Proactively purchased components when stock was running low on the floor, spearheaded key operational functions.
- Excelled in the sales and management roles, designing and executing initiatives to improve efficiency and workflow.
- Tracked the progress of weekly, monthly, quarterly and annual objectives, coordinated daily customer service operations.
- Evaluated employee performance and identified hiring and training needs, confidently supervised and motivated staff.
- Accurately monitored operating costs, budgets and resources while suggesting sales training programs and techniques.
- Communicated with clients and evaluated their needs, demonstrated ability for conflict resolution and problem solving.

## **Education & Certifications**

Nashville Software School – Full Stack Web Development Program – 07/2019 to 03/2020

University of Texas at Tyler – Bachelor of Business Management

# Project Links

BackLog: https://github.com/mstiles01/Backlog

Backlog is a movie lovers tracking app. You can add a title to your collection, with Director, Release Date, Poster Image. Then you add it to to a list to easily file what you've seen!

Backlog uses C# with MVC, .NET, <u>ADO.NET</u>, and Entity/Identity Frameworks. It also uses the following technologies: Bootstrap 4, Jquery, JavaScript, React.Js, HTML5, CSS3, SQL.

BreakBread: <a href="https://github.com/mstiles01/Break-Bread-Capstone">https://github.com/mstiles01/Break-Bread-Capstone</a>

BreakBread is a community baking app. A user can create a profile, create a recipe book, create a recipe, and post a recipe to the community baking tab. If another user sees your recipe they can clone it to one of their own recipe books, and modify it, without modifying the original users recipe.

BreakBread uses JavaScript with the React.Js library. It also uses the following technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 4, JSON